Ari Abramowitz Full Stack Web Developer

ariabr.netlify.app linkedin.com/in/ariabr github.com/ariabr

Summary

Full stack web developer with experience in both startup and agile environments. I am a creative, organized and methodical problem solver with strong writing skills and a background in philosophy. I have a drive to learn new technologies and I am always ready for a new challenge and the opportunity to bring another product to life.

Skills

Frontend: JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Material-UI

Backend / Databases: Python, Django, Flask, Node, Java, Spring, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Express, Firebase

Other Tools: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Jasmine, Pytest, Jira, Trello

Experience

Fullstack Software Engineer | Dynamic Healthcare Solutions

2020 - Present

- · Developed software to enable efficient AR management for 80,000+ residents in 80 facilities across the US
- · Improved efficiency of lab processing 2,000+ COVID tests per day by building an app to track sample history
- · Worked on a team of 6 developers in an Agile framework
- · Contributed to the process of transforming business requirements into actionable tickets
- Improved code quality by performing peer code reviews
- · Wrote clear and detailed documentation to ease future development

Software Developer | Taryag Analytics

2019 - 2020

- · Primary developer for a text mining and analytics startup
- Enabled 2020 Q1 beta launch by developing the frontend and backend for 6 new analysis features, including a sentence structure analyzer, a word cloud generator, and multiple text comparison tools
- · Improved comparative analysis capabilities by building a web-scraping ETL process to load new source data

Powered by Sefaria Contest

2020

- · Frontend developer for team building a 3D family tree visualizer for the Powered by Sefaria contest
- · Awarded Honorable Mention and featured as a showcase project on the company's website

Projects

2018 - 2020

- · Ezrat Nashim DB: Crowdsourced database designed to help users assess local synagogue options
- · Spotifake: Frontend-only music player application
- · Slaq: Chat app where users can sign in, create rooms and read, send, edit and delete messages
- Tirred: Discussion board where users sign up, add posts and vote and comment on posts

Open Source

2020

· Mindful Internet Use: Coded bug fix for Chrome productivity extension with 400+ users

Education

Continuing Education

continuing Education	
· Test-Driven Development with Python (Harry Percival)	2021
· The Complete Junior to Senior Web Developer Roadmap (Andrei Neagoie, Udemy)	2020
· The Ultimate Java Mastery Series (Code with Mosh)	2020
Bloc Web Developer Track	2019

- · Built 5 cloud-hosted web-apps as part of an 8-month apprentice-style coding bootcamp
- Mastered fundamental principles of software engineering and web development through project-based learning

Rutgers University | BA | Summa Cum Laude | GPA: 3.94

2018

- · Majors: Philosophy, Jewish Studies; Minor: Religion
- · Semester Abroad: Honors Program, The Hebrew University of Jerusalem
- · Honor societies: Phi Beta Kappa; Natl. Society of Collegiate Scholars; Natl. Society of Leadership and Success